# Juan Diego Garita Segura

# Android Developer

I have 5 years of experience as a mobile developer, my carrier started with android development written in java for small startup companies in Costa Rica. Growing demands on other areas, I had started to learn about iOS development and Kotlin - architecture components as well. I have experience in Scrum and Kanban methodologies and truely believe in techniques as pair programming, TDD and others. As a team player, I have had the chance to work on CI/CD, so I feel very confident in working with those environments and working on automated builds. Finally, as TDD lover, I always try to increase the test coverage of any project that I'm working on by using unit and automation testing as required.

# **Work History**

# 2017-07 - **N**

# Current

# Mobile Developer

Trusona

- Work off of backlog to direct development activities and priorities
- Generate code that is easy-to-understand and effective
- Create code in an efficient and timely manner in order to maintain delivery and release deadlines
- Use TDD, automated testing procedures and self-review technics to ensure you are delivering the highest quality, bug-free code possible
- Work collaboratively across the existing development team and with each individual team member

### 2016-11 -2017-07

## **Android Developer**

Gorilla Logic

- Designed and developed an Android app in the medical area.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to define, design, and ship new features.

### Contact

#### **Address**

Costa Rica, San Jose

#### Phone

849-690-25

#### E-mail

juandiegogarita@gmail.co m

#### LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/jd06

#### **WWW**

https://juandiegogarita.github.io/

### Skills

Android

Excellent

Java

Very Good

Kotlin

Very Good

IOS



- Worked directly with the UX/UI team to attempt to implement a unique user interface to the iOS and Android applications.
- Worked on bug fixing and improving application performance.

#### 2015-01 -Software Developer Senior Analyst 2016-11

Accenture Interactive

- Designed and developed advanced applications for the Android platform.
- Worked closely with UI/UX teams to document and scope new features.
- Designed and developed an Android Interface SDK to allow easy access for developers to the backend.
- Designed and documented the high-level architecture of the app.

#### 2014-09 -**Android Developer**

2014-12

Display Solutions

- Developed a Marketing based app for products of different brands.
- The UX was targeted at commercial tablets.
- Designed the UI flow and interaction based on the client's needs.
- Developed and designed a solution which allowed getting details about products, as well as sending products information to users by email and saving statistics remotely regarding tablet usages without interrupting user interaction.
- Additionally, the app allowed displaying product's pictures using custom transitions and animations.

### Education

0010 01	Distance of Madella Assessed David
2014-08	Latina University
2011-01 -	Bachelor of Software Engineering

#### 2013-01 -Diploma of Mobile Android Development 2013-12 Cenfotec University

#### Diploma of Advanced Android Application 2015-01 -2015-12 Dev

Cenfotec University